{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 43, "src": "Government Shutdown Debate Fuels House Republican Civil War", "tgt": "Дебаты о закрытии правительства подпитывают гражданскую войну республиканцев в Палате представителей", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 62, "end_i": 75, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 9, "end_i": 30, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "59", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 44, "src": "Conservative spending hawks in the House of Representatives bucked party leadership today - derailing a series of votes - in protest of Speaker Mike Johnson's recent spending deal with Democratic leadership that they feel does not go far enough in fiscal reductions.", "tgt": "Консервативные \"ястребы\" в Палате представителей сегодня выступили против руководства партии, сорвав ряд голосований в знак протеста против недавнего соглашения спикера Майка Джонсона с руководством демократов о расходах, которое, по их мнению, не предусматривает достаточных бюджетных сокращений.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "75", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 45, "src": "While the Louisiana Republican can avoid confronting the issue for now, on January 19 the country will face its deadline to pass four of 12 annual spending bills. Johnson has publicly stated that he would not support a \"continuing resolution\" (CR) to extend the deadline on these four bills to the February 2 due date for the remaining eight.", "tgt": "Хотя республиканец из Луизианы может пока избегать этого вопроса, 19 января стране предстоит принять четыре из 12 ежегодных законопроектов о расходах. Джонсон публично заявил, что не поддержит \"продолжающуюся резолюцию\" (CR) о продлении срока рассмотрения этих четырех законопроектов до 2 февраля - даты, назначенной для остальных восьми.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 83, "end_i": 99, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "90", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 46, "src": "However, with that deadline just 9 days away, Senate Republican Leader Mitch McConnell has said Congress will need to pass a CR to keep things open, meaning the speaker may soon break a promise he made, largely to appease his right flank. Such a maneuver could ignite a heated ideological battle in a closely divided House over the GOP's role in spending cuts that may see the government face a partial shutdown or Johnson removed from his job.", "tgt": "Однако, поскольку до истечения этого срока осталось всего 9 дней, лидер республиканцев в Сенате Митч Макконнелл заявил, что Конгрессу необходимо будет принять CR, чтобы сохранить работу правительства. Это означает, что спикер может вскоре нарушить данное им обещание, в основном для того, чтобы успокоить свой правый фланг. Такой маневр может спровоцировать ожесточенную идеологическую борьбу в сильно разделенной Палате представителей по поводу роли Республиканской партии в сокращении расходов, из-за чего правительство может столкнуться с частичным закрытием или Джонсон может лишиться своей должности.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 159, "end_i": 161, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 169, "end_i": 198, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 552, "end_i": 560, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "50", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 47, "src": "\"I've been very clear that CRs are not the way to fund our government that the Budget Act of 1974 calls for us to pass the 12 appropriation bills,\" Congressman Matt Rosendale of Montana told Newsweek. \"We've had ample time to do that, and if the leadership does not direct the committees to get the work done and the members to be able to vote upon it, that therein lies the breakdown.\"", "tgt": "\"Я совершенно ясно дал понять, что CR - это не способ финансирования нашего правительства, поскольку Закон о бюджете 1974 года требует от нас принятия 12 законопроектов об ассигнованиях\", - сказал Newsweek конгрессмен Мэтт Розендейл из Монтаны. \"У нас было достаточно времени, чтобы сделать это, и если руководство не даст указаний комитетам выполнить работу, а членам - проголосовать за нее, то в этом и заключается проблема\".", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 35, "end_i": 37, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 362, "end_i": 367, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "62", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 48, "src": "House Speaker Mike Johnson is pictured in the U.S. Capitol on December 12, 2023, in Washington, D.C. Johnson faces an unruly Republican conference that cannot reach an agreement on government spending levels. Photo by Kevin Dietsch/Getty Images", "tgt": "Спикер Палаты представителей Майк Джонсон запечатлен в Капитолии США 12 декабря 2023 года в Вашингтоне, округ Колумбия. Джонсон сталкивается с неуправляемой фракцией республиканцев, которые не могут прийти к соглашению об уровнях государственных расходов. Фото Кевина Дитша / Getty Images", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 42, "end_i": 51, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 128, "end_i": 139, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "66", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 49, "src": "Rosendale, a member of the hard-right Freedom Caucus, was one of the individuals who derailed the Wednesday votes. He views the top line number in Johnson's deal as being too high and as doing too little to cut the $34 trillion national debt.", "tgt": "Розендейл, член ультраправой фракции \"Фридом кокус\", был одним из тех, кто сорвал голосование в среду. Он считает, что верхняя планка в сделке Джонсона слишком высока и что она делает слишком мало для сокращения государственного долга в 34 триллиона долларов.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 173, "end_i": 182, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 119, "end_i": 132, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 134, "end_i": 141, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 38, "end_i": 49, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "65", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 50, "src": "Rosendale was also among the 71 Republicans who opposed the Fiscal Responsibility Act struck between Democrats and former Speaker Kevin McCarthy, a deal that set the parameters for Johnson's recent negotiation with Senate Democratic Leader Charles Schumer.", "tgt": "Розендейл также был в числе 71 республиканца, выступавших против Закона о фискальной ответственности, заключенного между демократами и бывшим спикером Кевином Маккарти, - соглашения, которое определило параметры недавних переговоров Джонсона с лидером демократов в Сенате Чарльзом Шумером.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 31, "end_i": 43, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "92", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 51, "src": "Johnson celebrated his deal for cutting an estimated $16 billion in spending, but the Freedom Caucus believes he could have gotten more. Moderate Republicans who backed McCarthy's deal see that stance as unrealistic and running counter to the Republican goal of forcing Congress to pass the 12 individual spending bills as opposed to the \"omnibus\" measure of recent years, which combined those 12 bills into one vote.", "tgt": "Джонсон праздновал свою сделку сокращением расходов примерно на 16 миллиардов долларов, но фракция \"Фридом кокус\" считает, что он мог бы добиться большего. Умеренные республиканцы, поддержавшие сделку Маккарти, считают такую позицию нереалистичной и идущей вразрез с целью республиканцев заставить Конгресс принять 12 отдельных законопроектов о расходах, а не \"всеобъемлющий\" законопроект последних лет, который объединял эти 12 законопроектов в одно голосование.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 31, "end_i": 41, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 100, "end_i": 111, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 451, "end_i": 461, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "69", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 52, "src": "\"New year, same idiotic behavior by some,\" New York Republican Representative Mike Lawler told Newsweek. \"We're not doing an omnibus, so each bill is going to have to be dealt with at conference and negotiated. Obviously, the reality is we're probably gonna need more time to do that. And I don't support a government shutdown, so I have no problem with doing a short-term CR that allows for this process to be completed.\"", "tgt": "\"Новый год, такое же идиотское поведение некоторых\", - сказал Newsweek представитель республиканской партии от штата Нью-Йорк Майк Лоулер. \"Мы не готовим всеобъемлющий законопроект, поэтому каждый законопроект придется рассматривать на конференции и согласовывать. Очевидно, реальность такова, что нам, вероятно, потребуется больше времени для этого. И я не поддерживаю закрытие правительства, поэтому у меня нет проблем с краткосрочным CR, который позволит завершить этот процесс\".", "doc_id": "test-en-news_newsweek.63908", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 233, "end_i": 246, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 370, "end_i": 377, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 437, "end_i": 438, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "60", "system": "Dubformer", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 682, "src": "Cheers, y'all. Now check it out. I really didn't even eat enough to be wiping my mouth, but I can tell you this, my mouth is salivating. You know what I mean? So look, this is what I'm trying to do. You guys let me know down in the comment section below, what would you do? What type of veggie would you serve this with? And don't forget, this is a budget friendly meal, alright. So let me just go ahead and pour myself a glass of this great coupgate. Yes, sir.", "tgt": "Приветствую всех. Теперь смотрите. Я даже не съел достаточно, чтобы вытирать рот, но могу сказать вам, что у меня слюнки текут. Понимаете, о чем я? Так вот, вот что я пытаюсь сделать. Дайте мне знать в комментариях ниже, что бы вы сделали? Какой овощ вы бы подали к этому? И не забывайте, это бюджетное блюдо, ясно? Так что позвольте мне просто налить себе бокал этого отличного купажа. Да, сэр.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_--Dq6kFSRDE_004", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 25, "end_i": 32, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 379, "end_i": 384, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "67", "system": "Claude-3.5", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "--Dq6kFSRDE_004.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--Dq6kFSRDE"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 717, "src": "South Wales Four Piece. The Now are proud to release their debut album Too Hot To Handle via True Music, and Callum joins me now. How are you doing, Callum? How's it going? Yeah, all good. Good yourself. Yes, I'm very good. Thank you. It's a privilege to speak to yourselves because I've been listening to your music quite a lot and since 2023. So I'm just loving the music, and I think it's something that would definitely need in the charts these days.", "tgt": "South Wales Four Piece. The Now с гордостью выпускают свой дебютный альбом Too Hot To Handle на лейбле True Music, и Каллум присоединяется ко мне. Как у тебя дела, Каллум? Как дела? Да, все хорошо. Веди себя хорошо. Да, у меня все очень хорошо получается. Спасибо». Для меня большая честь поговорить с вами, потому что я довольно много слушаю вашу музыку, начиная с 2023 года. Так что мне просто нравится музыка, и я думаю, что в наши дни это то, что определенно должно быть в чартах.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_5Ohwuu0GuMA_000", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 198, "end_i": 213, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 244, "end_i": 253, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 0, "end_i": 21, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "50", "system": "ONLINE-G", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "5Ohwuu0GuMA_000.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Ohwuu0GuMA"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 690, "src": "The question is, like countless other claimed Neolithic ruins, how did they achieve such feats? How did they lift such enormous stones? Were they, like we have posited many times before, the remnants of a once advanced yet destroyed ancient civilization, we find such possibilities, in particular, the men here of Agra, highly compelling.", "tgt": "Вопрос в том, как они достигли таких высот, как сотни других заявленных неолитических руин. Как они подняли такие огромные камни? Были ли они, как мы уже неоднократно утверждали, остатками уничтоженной древней цивилизации, мы находим такие возможности, в частности, мужчины здесь в Агре, очень убедительны.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_07FOJFFqOYc_002", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 61, "end_i": 70, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 234, "end_i": 250, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 226, "end_i": 233, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 282, "end_i": 285, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 294, "end_i": 304, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 37, "end_i": 41, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 31, "end_i": 36, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "58", "system": "IKUN", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "07FOJFFqOYc_002.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=07FOJFFqOYc"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 226, "src": "Moon landing time (about an hour to go) https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/intuitive-machines-1-lunar-landing/", "tgt": "Время посадки на Луну (остался примерно час) https://plus.nasa.gov/scheduled-video/intuitive-machines-1-lunar-landing/", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 227, "src": "The lander is about the size of old UK telephone box...", "tgt": "Аппарат для посадки примерно размером со старую телефонную будку в Великобритании...", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 228, "src": "3 minutes to go...", "tgt": "Осталось 3 минуты...", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 229, "src": "They had to patch some extra lasers into the landing system, hence the earlier delay: https://twitter.com/SciGuySpace/status/1760800168473928104", "tgt": "Им пришлось внести в систему посадки дополнительные лазеры, отсюда и ранее замедление: https://twitter.com/SciGuySpace/status/1760800168473928104", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 69, "end_i": 73, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "83", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 230, "src": "60 seconds...", "tgt": "60 секунд...", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 231, "src": "No comms yet...", "tgt": "Пока нет связи...", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 232, "src": "Live feed says that they have a signal", "tgt": "Прямая трансляция сообщает, что у них есть сигнал", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 233, "src": "\"We're on the surface and transmitting\"", "tgt": "\"Мы на поверхности и передаем сигнал\"", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111977766001055104", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "GPT-4", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 6, "src": "Adapt the old, accommodate the new to solve issue", "tgt": "Приспосабливайте старое, адаптируйте новое, чтобы решить проблему", "doc_id": "test-en-news_brisbanetimes.com.au.228963", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 7, "src": "At the precinct level, we just need to look at the Sydney CBD as an example of an area which has grown from its pre-settlement landscape into a two-storey city, from a maximum height of 150 feet to the soaring towers of today. At a much scaled-down level, the same can occur across Sydney's town centres located around transport nodes. Inner suburbs must also evolve, with a swing to more affordable apartment living at heights below the tree tops on key sites. Of course, the new growth in housing needs to be well-designed and trees, landscaping and parks need to be included along with other essential infrastructure.", "tgt": "На уровне округов нам просто нужно посмотреть на Сиднейский центр города в качестве примера района, который вырос из своего первоначального ландшафта в двухэтажный город, от максимальной высоты в 150 футов до взлетающих небоскребов сегодня. На более скромном уровне это может произойти по всему центру Сиднея, расположенному вокруг транспортных узлов. Внутренние пригороды также должны эволюционировать, с переходом к более доступному жилью на уровне деревьев на ключевых местах. Конечно, новое строительство жилья должно быть хорошо спроектировано, а деревья, ландшафт и парки должны быть включены вместе с другими необходимыми инфраструктурными объектами.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_brisbanetimes.com.au.228963", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 49, "end_i": 71, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 140, "end_i": 148, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 209, "end_i": 218, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 241, "end_i": 265, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 289, "end_i": 308, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 441, "end_i": 458, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 459, "end_i": 477, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 489, "end_i": 513, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "50", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 8, "src": "Our planning system also needs to adapt so that planners in suburban councils, who seem to be less supportive of change, are not the only determinants of the future shape of their suburbs. A way forward could be to have an independent decision-making body that championed quality design as long as it fitted below the tree tops and incorporated family living, large balconies, common gardens and presented a friendly appearance. This could be a role for the current NSW government architect working within a carefully crafted complying code.", "tgt": "Наше планировочное управление также должно адаптироваться, чтобы планировщики советов в пригородах, которые, кажется, менее поддерживают изменения, не были единственными определяющими факторами будущего облика своих пригородов. Путь вперед мог бы заключаться в создании независимого органа принятия решений, который бы отстаивал качественный дизайн, пока он соответствовал деревьям, включал семейное жилье, большие балконы, общие сады и имел дружелюбный вид. Это могла бы быть роль нынешнего правительственного архитектора штата Новый Южный Уэльс, работающего в соответствии с тщательно разработанным кодексом.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_brisbanetimes.com.au.228963", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 5, "end_i": 28, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 65, "end_i": 76, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 78, "end_i": 97, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 118, "end_i": 135, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 228, "end_i": 239, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 283, "end_i": 306, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 350, "end_i": 380, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 383, "end_i": 389, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 424, "end_i": 428, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 437, "end_i": 441, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 492, "end_i": 521, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "41", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 9, "src": "Over the past decade, our lives have changed through technology, with many working from home, and Sydney has gained an impressive network of metro and light rail systems. Our ability to purchase online has changed the way we shop, and friends and family seem closer because of smartphone communication. All of these adaptations from one system to another can also occur in our built environment through a planning focus on adaptive reuse rather than preferencing heritage preservation.", "tgt": "За последние десять лет наш образ жизни изменился благодаря технологиям, и Сидней получил впечатляющую сеть метро и легкого транспорта. Наша способность покупать онлайн изменила то, как мы покупаем, и наши друзья и семья кажутся ближе благодаря коммуникации с помощью смартфона. Все эти адаптации от одной системы к другой также могут произойти в нашем окружающем пространстве с помощью планирования, ориентированного на адаптивное использование, а не на предпочтение сохранения наследия.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_brisbanetimes.com.au.228963", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 116, "end_i": 133, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 178, "end_i": 197, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 245, "end_i": 276, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 345, "end_i": 375, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 287, "end_i": 295, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 421, "end_i": 444, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 447, "end_i": 466, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "60", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 10, "src": "Chris Johnson is a former NSW government architect (1995-2005) and executive director, NSW Department of Planning (2005-2009). He was CEO of Urban Taskforce Australia between 2011 and 2019.", "tgt": "Крис Джонсон — бывший архитектор правительства штата Новый Южный Уэльс (1995-2005) и исполнительный директор Департамента планирования штата Новый Южный Уэльс (2005-2009). Он был генеральным директором Урбан Таскфорс Австралия с 2011 по 2019 год.", "doc_id": "test-en-news_brisbanetimes.com.au.228963", "domain": "news", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 743, "src": "With his general purpose military markings, the Guinean pufferfish doesn't mind being seen. The Atlantic lizardfish doesn't bother with disguises at all. It simply shimmies into the sand. This may fool both its prey and its predators. But it won't fool the pufferfish patrol.", "tgt": "С общими военными маркировками, гвинейский пuffersfish не боится быть замеченным. Атлантический ящер рыба вообще не заботится о маскировке. Она просто скользит в песок. Это может обмануть как ее добычу, так и ее хищников. Но это не обманет патруль пuffersfish.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_Fhach-AU5Ko_020", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 2, "end_i": 29, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 43, "end_i": 53, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 96, "end_i": 104, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 151, "end_i": 158, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 160, "end_i": 166, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 248, "end_i": 258, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "50", "system": "Llama3-70B", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "Fhach-AU5Ko_020.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fhach-AU5Ko"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 166, "src": "Jakob Nielsen’s all-in on AI is melting my brain.", "tgt": "Всеобъемлющее мнение Джейкоба Нильсена о ИИ разрушает мой мозг.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 0, "end_i": 19, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "79", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 167, "src": "From his latest newsletter: https://jakobnielsenphd.substack.com/p/ux-roundup-20240219", "tgt": "Из последнего бюллетеня: https://jakobnielsenphd.substack.com/p/ux-roundup-20240219", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 14, "end_i": 22, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "83", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 168, "src": "I need to document this crap.", "tgt": "Мне нужно документально оформить этот хлам.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 10, "end_i": 31, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 33, "end_i": 41, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "68", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 169, "src": "@user13 Holy shit, that's delusional", "tgt": "@user13 Боже мой, это бред", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 170, "src": "@user14 @user13 the eliminating craft bit is incredibly gross, but I can't get over the ‘entertainment just for me' fetish.", "tgt": "@user14 @user13 удаляющий корабль очень отвратителен, но я не могу перестать восхищаться фетишем «развлечений только для меня».", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 16, "end_i": 32, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "50", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 171, "src": "it makes sense that ai revenge of boardroom derangement has metastasized from all creativity is fungible to there is no value in shared experience", "tgt": "понятно, что искусственный интеллект метастазирует из всех видов творчества, и нет никакой ценности в совместном опыте", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 37, "end_i": 49, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 54, "end_i": 74, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "28", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 172, "src": "it must suck to be these people. i can't imagine how awful their inner life must be", "tgt": "надо быть такими людьми, чтобы это было ужасно. я не могу представить, насколько ужасной должна быть внутренняя жизнь этих людей", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 0, "end_i": 45, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 101, "end_i": 116, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "33", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 173, "src": "@user15 @user14 I feel like \"shared experience\" is a defining factor of entertainment. Either sharing among an audience or an entertainer sharing with an audience. When you make your own entertainment, just for you, you're just playing with yourself", "tgt": "@user15 @user14 Я думаю, что «общий опыт» — это определяющий фактор развлечений. Либо поделиться с аудиторией, либо поделиться с аудиторией. Когда вы делаете свой собственный развлекательный контент только для себя, вы просто играете с собой", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 30, "end_i": 34, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 97, "end_i": 108, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 234, "end_i": 240, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "60", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 174, "src": "@user13 personally I basically think that shared experience is kind of essential to all we do, other things feel alienated (often, not 100% of course)", "tgt": "@user13 лично я считаю, что общий опыт — это, по сути, очень важный элемент всего, что мы делаем, другие вещи кажутся чужими (часто, конечно, не полностью)", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 28, "end_i": 32, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 118, "end_i": 123, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "75", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 175, "src": "@user14 yeah, even solitary means are generally for a shared ends.", "tgt": "@user14 да, даже одиночные средства обычно используются для общей цели.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_111976217731399552", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 17, "end_i": 34, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "76", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 417, "src": "Getting my eyes checked, because there was a decent deal for it here, and my left eye’s been weird for some time now, so maybe they can tell me something what’s happening.", "tgt": "Иду проверять зрение, потому что тут подвернулась неплохая скидка, да и левый глаз уже давно как-то странно себя ведёт, может, скажут, что с ним не так.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 418, "src": "I’m splurging on a new set of frames, these red ones I reeeeally like.", "tgt": "Я трачусь на новую оправу, эти красные мне оооочень нравятся.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 419, "src": "So, apparently the ghost image my left eye sees isn’t too much of a concern. But I need basically varifocals too. So the lenses have a combo of those. Not the full on varifocals but something in between those and ”normal” glasses (no idea of the terminology in English).", "tgt": "Так что, видимо, призрачное изображение, которое видит мой левый глаз, не вызывает особого беспокойства. Но мне, по сути, тоже нужны прогрессивные линзы. Так что в линзах есть их комбинация. Не совсем прогрессивные, а что-то среднее между ними и «обычными» очками (не знаю, как это называется по-английски).", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 17, "end_i": 38, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 162, "end_i": 169, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 171, "end_i": 188, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 194, "end_i": 199, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "66", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 420, "src": "While this was being told to me, I made a decision to get another pair, and that pair are these.", "tgt": "Пока мне это рассказывали, я принял решение купить другую пару, и эта пара - вот она.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 421, "src": "@user36 I like both the glasses you posted, these are a really nice colour...makes me want new ones 😂", "tgt": "@user36 Мне нравятся обе пары очков, которые ты запостил, у них очень красивый цвет... аж самой захотелось новые 😂", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 422, "src": "@user37 My current collection consists of two green pairs, one blue-purple and one pinkish lilac pair. The last one’s at home currently, but I usually carry at least two pairs with me.", "tgt": "@user37 Моя текущая коллекция состоит из двух зеленых пар, одной сине-фиолетовой и одной розовато-лиловой. Последняя сейчас дома, но обычно я ношу с собой как минимум две пары.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 423, "src": "I’ve been tempted to get sunglasses with prescriptions but they don’t make these for that purpose 😆 I bought the golden aviators on a whim one birthday.", "tgt": "Я подумывал купить солнцезащитные очки с диоптриями, но их не делают для этой цели 😆 Я купил золотые авиаторы спонтанно на один из дней рождения.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 56, "end_i": 81, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "84", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 424, "src": "@user36 that second pair is really nice! I love buying glasses...I never throw them out but somehow I can't find any of the others?! Mine are rainbow coloured at the moment, I need some sunglasses too... but if you need prescription they're so ugly 😂", "tgt": "@user36, вторая пара действительно классная! Обожаю покупать очки... Никогда их не выбрасываю, но почему-то не могу найти остальные?! У меня сейчас радужные, ещё нужны солнцезащитные... но если нужны с диоптриями, то они такие страшные 😂", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112112980319428992", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 122, "end_i": 130, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 148, "end_i": 155, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "78", "system": "Gemini-1.5-Pro", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 709, "src": "So my dad can't give me rides to work. And for me, work is about 27 miles away. So there and back would be nearly a hundred dollars a day with Uber. I haven't looked at Lyft. I could have, I guess, that makes sense. But I didn't have rental on my auto insurance, so that's my fault. So I guess I could have tried to do that and get that set up and tried to get a rental while I was down and out of a car. But even then, a rental would cover seven days. I'm going to sneeze, hold on. That sneeze sucked.", "tgt": "Итак, папа не может подвозить меня до работы. А мне ехать примерно 27 миль до работы. На убере это будет почти 100 долларов туда и обратно. Я не проверял Lyft, хотя и мог бы, наверное, это было бы осмысленно. Но у меня не было страховки на вождение арендованных автомобилей, сам виноват. Так что, наверное, я мог бы попробовать разобраться со страховкой и попробовать взять машину в аренду, пока у меня не было своей. Но и в этом случае арендованной авто не хватило бы на 7 дней. Сейчас чихну, подождите. Ужасный чих.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_3MTATdXzFC4_009", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 185, "end_i": 206, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "91", "system": "refA", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "3MTATdXzFC4_009.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MTATdXzFC4"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 766, "src": "Affordable furniture DIYs are always a hit here on Lone Fox, so I wanted to share with you guys how I created this nightstand from a simple crate from IKEA. So this is the Nagle crate, which you can pick up for about $10 at IKEA. And I went ahead and I started off by just constructing it based off the instructions. You have to just screw all of the elements together. And once they are all screwed up, you have a basic wooden crate. Now on the bottom of the wooden crate, I wanted to add a leg, so I elevated it off the floor with these little wooden trinket dishes or like little wooden trays that I found at the craft store as well. They are just a simple wood, very similar to the one from IKEA, and I just e 6,000 these down. You could also use a nail gun if you'd like to. And once you are done, you have a very simple, minimal nightstand.", "tgt": "Доступные самоделки из мебели всегда популярны здесь, на Lone Fox, поэтому я хотел поделиться с вами тем, как я создал эту тумбочку из простого ящика от IKEA. Это ящик Nagle, который можно купить примерно за 10 долларов в IKEA. И я сразу же начал собирать его, следуя инструкции. Вам просто нужно все элементы собрать вместе с помощью винтов. И когда все собрано, у вас получается обычный деревянный ящик. Теперь на дно деревянного ящика я хотел добавить ножку, поэтому я поднял его над полом с помощью этих маленьких деревянных подставок или каких-то маленьких деревянных подносов, которые я тоже нашел в магазине товаров для рукоделия. Они сделаны из простого дерева, очень похожего на дерево от IKEA, и я просто закрепил их. Вы также можете использовать степлер, если хотите. И когда вы закончите, у вас получится очень простая, минималистичная тумбочка.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_Q5coSYYa6z0_000", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 757, "end_i": 763, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "79", "system": "Unbabel-Tower70B", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "Q5coSYYa6z0_000.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q5coSYYa6z0"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 773, "src": "Okay, so let me explain. All right, so the problem is, if you look inside there, you see the wood siding, there's the old siding, and it buzz up to the shingles there. And then I put this over it. And what happens is the dirt collects there to that flashing.", "tgt": "Хорошо, тогда я объясню. Так вот, проблема в том, что если вы загляните внутрь, вы увидите деревянную обшивку, там старая обшивка, и она заходит под черепицу. И я положил это поверх нее. И что происходит, грязь скапливается там, на этом противотоке.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_RfoVF8wcZRI_000", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 8, "end_i": 22, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "82", "system": "Aya23", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "RfoVF8wcZRI_000.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RfoVF8wcZRI"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 588, "src": "my hedges are getting big.", "tgt": "мои живые изгороди становятся большими.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 589, "src": "well now they’re god damn huge lol", "tgt": "ну вот теперь они действительно огромные :D", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 590, "src": "new ath. i know what that means..", "tgt": "новый атлет, знаю, что это значит...", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 6, "end_i": 10, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "5", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 591, "src": "switch to cash, no more margin.", "tgt": "перейти на наличные, больше нет маржи.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 28, "end_i": 36, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "39", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 592, "src": "let’s tank the first week of the new year", "tgt": "подберем первую неделю нового года", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 0, "end_i": 7, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "42", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 594, "src": "lfg $sqqq", "tgt": "lfg $sqqq", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 595, "src": "lfg $tslq lol", "tgt": "lfg $tslq lol", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [], "esa_score": "100", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 596, "src": "waaaaahoooo!! lol", "tgt": "waaaaahoooo!! lol", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 0, "end_i": 16, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "0", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 597, "src": "come on nok, $3.74 let’s go.", "tgt": "nok, $3.74, поехали.", "doc_id": "test-en-social_112201850099412432", "domain": "social", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 0, "end_i": 2, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "33", "system": "IKUN-C", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": null}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 732, "src": "I didn't say that. You don't have to. You know better than anyone that violence begets violence every time. The council made the decision. The council is gone. We spend our entire lives. Entire millennia devoted to protecting life.", "tgt": "Я этого не говорил. Тебе и не нужно. Ты лучше, чем кто-либо другой, знаешь, что насилие порождает насилие. Совет принял решение. Совета больше нет. Мы потратили всю свою жизнь. Целые тысячелетия мы посвятили защите жизни.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_9GhGiB4KhTM_004", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": "missing", "end_i": "missing", "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "83", "system": "Yandex", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "9GhGiB4KhTM_004.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9GhGiB4KhTM"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 705, "src": "Well, it still sounds better than Pink Floyd, so in Manic Miner, you collect all the items on the screen and head to the goal. And you gotta do it before you run out of air or hit something. Hit what exactly? Weeds! You can die from touching grass. It sounds like half my fanbase. And did you notice I died from touching a weed that was on a completely different platform? I just went through the platform and then hit the weed. That's good game design, man. And then there's this asshole over here who's gone.", "tgt": "Ну, это все равно звучит лучше, чем Pink Floyd, так что в Manic Miner вы собираете все предметы на экране и направляетесь к финишу. И вы должны сделать это до того, как у вас закончится воздух или вы столкнетесь с чем-то. С чем именно? С сорняками! Вы можете умереть, коснувшись травы. Это похоже на половину моей фан-базы. И вы заметили, что я умер, столкнувшись с сорняком, который был на совершенно другой платформе? Я просто прошел через платформу, а потом столкнулся с сорняком. Это хорошее игровое дизайнерское решение, чувак. А потом был этот придурок, который ушел.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_33gJqN796Eo_000", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 48, "end_i": 54, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "85", "system": "Unbabel-Tower70B", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "33gJqN796Eo_000.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=33gJqN796Eo"}}
{"langs": "en-ru", "line_id": 728, "src": "Kim Jong-il said to the officials I shared a great leader's motor, served the working messes and let flowers bloom even on a rock, if this is the people's desire. This is my alpha and omega. This idea has been embedded in every aspect of the people's living in the solution of traffic problem for one thing.", "tgt": "Ким Чен Ир сказал чиновникам, что я разделяю мотор великого лидера, служу рабочим массам и даю цветам расцвести даже на скале, если это желание народа. Это моя альфа и омега. Эта идея была внедрена во всех аспектах жизни народа в решении проблемы движения, например.", "doc_id": "test-en-speech_6ji3tqZUynY_001", "domain": "speech", "esa_spans": [{"start_i": 228, "end_i": 254, "severity": "minor", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 45, "end_i": 50, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}, {"start_i": 30, "end_i": 32, "severity": "major", "error_type": null}], "esa_score": "62", "system": "Aya23", "annotator": "engrus7701", "speech_info": {"file": "6ji3tqZUynY_001.mp4", "youtube": "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6ji3tqZUynY"}}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Okay, so let me explain. All right, so the problem is, if you look inside there, you see the wood siding, there's the old siding, and it buzz up to the shingles there. And then I put this over it. And what happens is the dirt collects there to that flashing.", "tgt": "Bueno, d\u00e9jame explicarte. Bien, el problema es que, si miras hacia adentro, ver\u00e1s el revestimiento de madera; ah\u00ed est\u00e1 el revestimiento viejo, y se eleva hasta las tejas. Y luego lo cubr\u00ed con esto. Lo que sucede es que la suciedad se acumula en esa cinta met\u00e1lica.", "esa_score": "96"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Starr. The princess of Tamara. Comfortable, I hope. More bag rock! Oh! Such a formidable spirit. Your sister was wise to hand you over. Galar neck!", "tgt": "Starr. La princesa de Tamara. C\u00f3moda, espero. \u00a1M\u00e1s roca de bolsa! \u00a1Oh! \u00a1Qu\u00e9 esp\u00edritu formidable! Tu hermana fue sabia al entregarte. \u00a1Cuello de Galar!", "esa_score": "82"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "And when you download it, it should be a pretty quick, small file size. You're going to get an app that looks just like this. So I could click on that right now. And this is the view that you're going to see right away here. And so I'll talk about a few things with the lab. Now one thing to note is that the lab instructions for the lab worksheet that you're going to work on are pretty self explanatory. So really, the purpose of this video is to show you how to use the app itself.", "tgt": "Y cuando lo descargue, el proceso ser\u00e1 muy r\u00e1pido, ya que el archivo es peque\u00f1o. Obtendr\u00e1 una aplicaci\u00f3n que se ver\u00e1 exactamente como esta. Ahora podr\u00eda darle clic a esta. Esta es la pantalla que ver\u00e1 en seguida. Ahora hablar\u00e9 acerca de algunas cosas del laboratorio. Una cosa importante a tener en cuenta es que las instrucciones para el laboratorio en las que trabajar\u00e1 son bastante sencillas. En verdad, el prop\u00f3sito de este video es mostrarle c\u00f3mo utilizar la aplicaci\u00f3n en s\u00ed.", "esa_score": "90"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Politicians get it wrong when it comes to rent caps", "tgt": "Los pol\u00edticos se equivocan cuando se trata de los topes de alquiler", "esa_score": "82"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "There is always the temptation for politicians to intervene in situations where they think they can make a difference. Of course, if there was an obvious simple solution to a problem somebody with more knowledge and understanding of the problems would already have implemented it.", "tgt": "Siempre existe la tentaci\u00f3n para los pol\u00edticos de intervenir en situaciones donde creen que pueden marcar la diferencia. Por supuesto, si hubiera una soluci\u00f3n simple y obvia para un problema, alguien con m\u00e1s conocimiento y comprensi\u00f3n de los problemas ya la habr\u00eda implementado.", "esa_score": "93"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Thus, we had the introduction of the Cost of Living (Tenant protection) (Scotland) Act 2022 nearly 18 months ago which sought to cap rents for a limited period to ease the pressures of the cost-of-living crisis. What we find now from the latest Scottish Government statistics is that, in the last year alone, average rents have increased in all sized properties, ranging from the lowest rise of 11.7 per cent for one-bedroom to the highest figure of 14.3 per cent for two-bedroom homes. Every type of property (from one to four bedroom to a room in a property) has had a double digit increase in rents since the Cost of Living legislation was introduced in October 2022, exceeding the annual average increases in rents over the previous 12 years by a factor of at least three.", "tgt": "As\u00ed, hace casi 18 meses tuvimos la introducci\u00f3n de la Ley de Costo de Vida (Protecci\u00f3n del Inquilino) (Escocia) de 2022, que buscaba limitar los alquileres por un per\u00edodo limitado para aliviar las presiones de la crisis del costo de vida. Lo que encontramos ahora en las \u00faltimas estad\u00edsticas del Gobierno escoc\u00e9s es que, solo en el \u00faltimo a\u00f1o, los alquileres promedio han aumentado en propiedades de todos los tama\u00f1os, desde el aumento m\u00e1s bajo del 11,7 por ciento para las de un dormitorio hasta la cifra m\u00e1s alta del 14,3 por ciento para las viviendas de dos dormitorios. Todos los tipos de propiedades (desde una hasta cuatro habitaciones o una habitaci\u00f3n en una propiedad) han tenido un aumento de dos d\u00edgitos en los alquileres desde que se introdujo la legislaci\u00f3n sobre el Costo de Vida en octubre de 2022, superando los aumentos promedio anuales de alquileres de los 12 a\u00f1os anteriores por un factor de al menos tres.", "esa_score": "83"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "There were plenty of warnings from all involved in the housing sector that this would happen, but these went unheeded. An unwillingness to believe that market forces are what dictates prices rather than government has led to enormous rent price rises which could have been avoided with greater understanding, negotiation and discussion with the sector and a plan that understood the principles of supply and demand.", "tgt": "Hubo muchas advertencias de todos los involucrados en el sector de la vivienda de que esto suceder\u00eda, pero no se les prest\u00f3 atenci\u00f3n. La falta de voluntad para creer que las fuerzas del mercado son las que dictan los precios en lugar del gobierno ha llevado a enormes aumentos en los precios de los alquileres que podr\u00edan haberse evitado con un mayor entendimiento, negociaci\u00f3n y discusi\u00f3n con el sector y un plan que comprendiera los principios de oferta y demanda.", "esa_score": "92"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "With the Cost of Living Act legislation ending on 31 March 2024, a new consultation document seeks to extend controls on the level of rent increases that can be levied in the coming year. The consultation ends this Monday and proposes rents be set by the lowest of three comparators: open market rent; a landlord's proposed new rent; and a \"reasonable\" increase devised from a new taper system using comparison with a percentage of market rent.", "tgt": "Con la legislaci\u00f3n de la Ley del Costo de Vida que finaliza el 31 de marzo de 2024, un nuevo documento de consulta busca extender los controles sobre el nivel de aumentos de alquiler que se pueden imponer en el pr\u00f3ximo a\u00f1o. La consulta termina este lunes y propone que los alquileres se establezcan seg\u00fan el m\u00e1s bajo de tres comparadores: el alquiler de mercado abierto; el nuevo alquiler propuesto por el arrendador; y un aumento \"razonable\" derivado de un nuevo sistema escalonado que utiliza la comparaci\u00f3n con un porcentaje del alquiler de mercado.", "esa_score": "94"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Scottish tenants are likely to face further alarming rent increases if experts are not heeded (Picture: Adobe)", "tgt": "Los inquilinos escoceses probablemente enfrentar\u00e1n nuevos y alarmantes aumentos de alquiler si no se presta atenci\u00f3n a los expertos (Imagen: Adobe)", "esa_score": "94"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "This tapering proposal would set rent increases between 6 per cent and a maximum of 15 per cent which, ironically, would be higher than historic annual price rises. But, more importantly, this scheme would be unwieldy, overly complex and prohibitively expensive to monitor and implement. We already have a system involving the first-tier housing tribunal which rules on whether a rent increase is fair. This seems like adding further layers of bureaucracy with no gain for landlords or tenants.", "tgt": "Esta propuesta de reducci\u00f3n gradual establecer\u00eda aumentos de alquiler entre el 6 por ciento y un m\u00e1ximo del 15 por ciento que, ir\u00f3nicamente, ser\u00edan m\u00e1s altos que los aumentos anuales hist\u00f3ricos. Pero, m\u00e1s importante a\u00fan, este esquema ser\u00eda dif\u00edcil de manejar, excesivamente complejo y prohibitivamente costoso de monitorear e implementar. Ya tenemos un sistema que involucra al tribunal de vivienda de primera instancia, que dictamina si un aumento de alquiler es justo. Esto parece agregar m\u00e1s capas de burocracia sin beneficio alguno para propietarios o inquilinos.", "esa_score": "95"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Unfortunately, this consultation paper seems like a further attempt to impose controls on the sector. A far simpler solution would be to let the market return to normal, not impose external controls on rent levels, and the result will be lower rent increases than we have seen in the last 18 months. To stabilise rental prices in the long term then the government must encourage greater investment and growth in the private rented sector (PRS) while simultaneously funding a substantial growth in the supply of social housing. The greater the investment in the PRS the more stability will be created in the housing market. Increasing volumes in both the PRS and social housing markets will stabilise rents over time as demand meets supply and equilibrium is achieved. Only by adopting these measures will we start to address the current housing crisis. Anything else is simply not going to work.", "tgt": "Desafortunadamente, este documento de consulta parece un intento m\u00e1s de imponer controles sobre el sector. Una soluci\u00f3n mucho m\u00e1s simple ser\u00eda permitir que el mercado vuelva a la normalidad, no imponer controles externos sobre los niveles de alquiler, y el resultado ser\u00e1n aumentos de alquiler m\u00e1s bajos de los que hemos visto en los \u00faltimos 18 meses. Para estabilizar los precios de alquiler a largo plazo, el gobierno debe fomentar una mayor inversi\u00f3n y crecimiento en el sector de alquiler privado (PRS) mientras financia simult\u00e1neamente un crecimiento sustancial en la oferta de viviendas sociales. Cuanto mayor sea la inversi\u00f3n en el PRS, m\u00e1s estabilidad se crear\u00e1 en el mercado inmobiliario. El aumento de vol\u00famenes tanto en los mercados de PRS como de viviendas sociales estabilizar\u00e1 los alquileres con el tiempo a medida que la demanda se encuentre con la oferta y se logre el equilibrio. Solo adoptando estas medidas comenzaremos a abordar la crisis de vivienda actual. Cualquier otra cosa simplemente no va a funcionar.", "esa_score": "90"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Hello this is Nick from Review Outlaw. So what we're going to do today is to do a final walkthrough of the cabin we finished up. Pretty much getting to the end. This is the first room you walked into before you can finish, we finished that ceiling, got the walls all sheet rock painted this little border across here, got alarm system in.", "tgt": "Este es Nick de Review Outlaw. As\u00ed que lo que haremos hoy es dar un recorrido final por la caba\u00f1a que acabamos de terminar. Pr\u00e1cticamente estamos llegando al final. Esta es la primera habitaci\u00f3n a la que entras, antes de que termin\u00e1ramos el techo. Tenemos las paredes con tablayeso pintado, un peque\u00f1o borde aqu\u00ed, y el sistema de alarma instalado.", "esa_score": "91"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Welcome to CSA in Italy. CSA is believed to be an ancient Roman settlement. The site was excavated at least four times over the last century. What is there to excavate if Koa is originally a Roman site? Was the Pantheon in Rome excavated? No, the pantheon is even at the same ground level as the surrounding, contemporary buildings. And why is that? Because the pantheon was probably built during the Roman era, it is also almost cardinally oriented, which indicates that it cannot be very ancient.", "tgt": "Bienvenidos a CSA en Italia. Se cree que Cosa fue un antiguo asentamiento romano. El sitio fue excavado al menos cuatro veces durante el siglo pasado. \u00bfQu\u00e9 hay que excavar si Cosa es originalmente un sitio romano? \u00bfSe excav\u00f3 el Pante\u00f3n de Roma? No, el Pante\u00f3n est\u00e1 incluso al mismo nivel del suelo que los edificios contempor\u00e1neos que lo rodean. \u00bfY por qu\u00e9 es eso? Porque el Pante\u00f3n probablemente fue construido durante la \u00e9poca romana, tambi\u00e9n est\u00e1 orientado casi cardinalmente, lo que indica que no puede ser muy antiguo.", "esa_score": "96"}
{"langs": "en-es", "src": "Proper handling and disposal of waste at your auto repair facility is important for employee health, but also to avoid fines or significant legal settlements. Also, customers want to do business with companies that make an effort to proactively protect the environment and operate in a sustainable way. So what are seven ways you can do this? Number one, re-refining used oil. Don't just discard your old oil. With the right processes, oil can be fully re-refined and reused indefinitely without any reduction in quality.", "tgt": "El manejo y disposici\u00f3n adecuados de los residuos en su instalaci\u00f3n de reparaci\u00f3n de autom\u00f3viles es importante para la salud de los empleados, pero tambi\u00e9n para evitar multas o acuerdos legales significativos. Adem\u00e1s, los clientes quieren hacer negocios con empresas que se esfuerzan por proteger el medio ambiente de manera proactiva y operar de manera sostenible. Entonces, \u00bfcu\u00e1les son siete formas de hacer esto? N\u00famero uno, re-refinar aceite usado. No descarte simplemente su aceite viejo. Con los procesos adecuados, el aceite puede ser re-refinado por completo y reutilizado indefinidamente sin reducir su calidad.", "esa_score": "100"}
